It's a strange world, isn't it?
Blue Velvet is a mystery, thriller, crime film directed by David Lynch.
The discovery of a severed human ear found in a field leads a young man on an investigation related to a
beautiful, mysterious nightclub singer and a group of psychopathic criminals who have kidnapped her child.
Dorothy Vallens, played by Isabella Rossellini.
Jeffrey Beaumont, played by Kyle MacLachlan.
Frank Booth, played by Dennis Hopper.
Sandy Williams, played by Laura Dern.
Mrs. Williams, played by Hope Lange.
Ben, played by Dean Stockwell.
Blue Velvet is a 1986 American neo-noir mystery thriller
film written and directed by David Lynch.
The film stars Kyle MacLachlan, Isabella Rossellini, Dennis Hopper, and
Laura Dern, and is named after the 1951 song of the same name.
The film follows a college student who returns to his hometown and discovers a severed human ear in a
field, which leads him to uncover a criminal conspiracy involving a troubled nightclub singer.
The screenplay of Blue Velvet had been passed around multiple times in the late 1970s and early 1980s,
with several major studios declining it due to its strong sexual and violent content.
After the failure of his 1984 film Dune, Lynch made attempts at developing a more "personal story",
somewhat characteristic of the surrealist style displayed in his first film Eraserhead (1977).
The independent studio De Laurentiis Entertainment Group, owned at the time by Italian
film producer Dino De Laurentiis, agreed to finance and produce the film.
Blue Velvet initially received a divided critical response, with many
stating that its explicit content served little artistic purpose.
Nevertheless, the film earned Lynch his second nomination for the Academy Award for Best Director, and
received the year's Best Film and Best Director prizes from the National Society of Film Critics.
It came to achieve cult status.
As an example of a director casting against the norm, it was credited for revitalizing Hopper's career and for providing
Rossellini with a dramatic outlet beyond her previous work as a fashion model and a cosmetics spokeswoman.
In the years since, the film has been re-evaluated, and is widely regarded as one of Lynch's
magnum opus and is frequently cited as one of the greatest films of the 1980s.
Publications including Sight and Sound, Time, Entertainment Weekly and BBC
Magazine have ranked it among the greatest American films of all time.
In 2008, it was chosen by the American Film Institute as one
of the ten greatest American mystery films.
The film explores themes of drug dealer, small town,
sexual obsession, detective, nightclub.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.